本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
早上好啊 迪普
Morning, Dipper.
猜猜我是谁
Guess who.
真是求之不得啊
Oh, what joy.
这不是倒立哥么
If it isn't Mr. Upsidedownington.
上次见到你是在小学三年级了吧
How long has it been? Third grade maybe?
没错  我来这儿是要告诉你
That's right, and I'm here to deliver you
倒立哥专属好消息
an Upsidedownington-tastic message!
是不是我们都长大了
Is it the message that
不该再玩这么幼稚的游戏了
we're getting too old for this sort of thing?
其实差不多啦
Um, kinda, actually.
消息就是离我们的十三岁生日
It's that we're exactly one week away
只有恰好一个星期了
from our 13th birthday!
哇  我们的生日这么快就到了
Whoa! Our birthday's coming up already?
马上我们就能变成青少年了
Soon we're gonna be actual teenagers!
我总算能摆脱儿童杂志
Finally I can stop reading pre-teen magazines,
好好享受青少年杂志了
and start reading post-pre-teen magazines.
家长辅导级电影  我来了
PG-13 movies, here I come.
还有一年我们就能上高中了
And just one more year until high school.
高中啊  迪普
High school, Dipper!
女孩子会成长为女人
Where girls become women,
还会教我们那些知识
and they teach us stuff about...
你懂的
you know what.
三角函数吗
Trigonometry?
简直是迫不及待啊
Oh, yeah, baby.
好消息还不止这个
That's not the only good news coming up.
下个星期
In one week,
我的老男人马尾辫套装就要寄到了
my senior citizen ponytail kit is coming in the mail.
我  我总算是要熬出头了啊
I'm... I'm kinda going through some things.
下个星期  我奶奶总算允许我
In one week, my grandma is finally letting me
在床上吃饼干了
eat crackers on my bed.
未来一片大好啊  大家伙儿
The future is coming for us all, dudes.
-未来  -未来
- The future. - The future.
未来
The future!
不好意思  你在下巴上贴眼睛
I'm sorry, I can't take you seriously
根本严肃不起来
with that face on your chin.
迪普  哪双眼睛啊
What face, Dipper?
你又开始不好好说话了
You're doing the voice,
所以你肯定明白我是什么意思
so you obviously know what I'm talking about.
我才不知道你想说什么呢
I don't know what you're talking about.
你真是脑子搭错筋了
There is something wrong with you.
咱俩脑子都搭错筋了
There's something wrong with both of us.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： Enpistu
翻译： 战忽局副局座  Wizard小希  溪傲季
怪诞小镇  第二季第十七集
Gravity Falls  S02E17  Dipper and Mavel Vs The Future
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  cometwang
好了  聚会策划们
All right, party planners.
下个星期我们就要成为青少年
In one week, we become teenagers,
暑假也将要迎来尾声
and summer vacation winds to an end,
所以我们必须得把聚会开得史上第一棒
so we need to throw the greatest party of all time!
比如说用墨西哥糖果罐套糖果罐
I'm talkin' pinatas with tinier pinatas inside.
哈  梦想成真啊
Boom, dreams comin' true.
比如说把全镇的人都请来
I'm talkin' inviting everyone in town.
我看看
Let's see.
小矮人该怎么打交道呢
Where do we stand with the gnomes?
别急  傻小子和傻丫头
Not so fast, goofus and girl goofus.
那场僵尸危机之后
After that zombie incident,
谁也不准在我的房子里开聚会
no one's throwing another party at my house.
沙发垫子底下的僵尸骨头死活清不干净
I keep finding little bits of the undead in the couch cushions.
但是斯坦叔公  开聚会总不能没地盘吧
But Grunkle Stan, we need some roof to raise.
各位  你们可以租用重力泉高中的体育馆
Dude, you can rent out the Gravity Falls high school gym,
在那里开聚会啊
and have your party there.
那个地方一整个暑假都没人
That place is empty all summer long.
体育馆真是个好主意  苏斯
The gym's a great idea, Soos.
向高中进军
To the high school!
迪普  我脸着火了
Dipper, my face is on fire!
我马上回来
I'll just be a second.
阿福叔公  你还好吗
Hey, Uncle Ford, are you okay?
没啥事  我很好
Oh, yes, I'm fine.
我这么说是想让你赶紧过来
I just said that to make sure you'd come in here.
但是你的脸的确着火了
But your face is on fire.
没错  这样比刮胡子省事多了
Yes. It's much faster than shaving.
迪普  现在听好
Now listen, Dipper.
我有个很重要的任务
I have a very important mission,
而你是唯一能帮我的人
and you are the only one who can help me.
还记得我给你看的时空维度裂痕吗
Remember the rift in dimensional space-time I showed you?
出现裂缝了
It's cracking.
比尔期待的就是这一刻
This is what Bill has been waiting for.
如果缝隙破裂  将把我们所处的
If it breaks, it'll cause reality as we know it
现实世界搅得翻天覆地
to become completely unraveled.
这个灾难性的理论假说
A hypothetical and catastrophic event
我称其为“湮没之日”
I call Weirdmageddon.
比尔就在外面  他会尝试一切诡计
Bill is out there, and he'd use any trick
从欺骗思想到人身控制
from deception to outright possession
只为这一刻的到来
to make this happen.
为了芸芸众生  我们必须阻止他
But for the sake of humanity, we mustn't let him.
-我们该怎么办  -把裂痕补好
- What do we do? - We patch the rift.
我在半路上解释
I'll explain on the way.
-等等  梅宝怎么办  -没关系  迪普
- Wait. What about Mabel? - It's okay, Dipper.
你就放心跟阿福叔公
You should totally go with Grunkle Ford
去拯救世界什么的吧
to save the world or whatever.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我们一整个星期都会忙活生日趴
We're gonna be doing birthday junk all week.
再说了  我把对讲机都装好了
Plus, I packed those walkie-talkies.
这个给我的聚会策划用
Here's one for my party mission,
这个给你的救世任务用
and one for your smarty mission.
我已经说过全宇宙
Ahem. I did mention that the fate of the universe
都命悬一线了  对吧
is at stake, didn't I?
动作快点  快来不及了
Hurry. We haven't much time.
好了  迪普  这是你第一次和阿福出任务
Okay, Dipper, it's your first big mission with Ford,
这是证明自己的机会
a chance to prove yourself.
千万别搞砸了
Don't mess this up.
我没事
I'm all right.
哇  苏斯  你不是说这里没人吗
Whoa, Soos, I thought you said this place was empty.
哟  哥们儿们好
My dogs, what up?
温蒂  你来这里干嘛
Wendy, what are you doing here?
呃  高中开学报到啊
Ugh. High school registration.
你猜怎么着  明年我也是高中生了
Oh! You know, I'm only a year away from high school myself.
你觉得高中经历更像是
Would you say your experience
浪漫喜剧还是搞笑闹剧呢
is more rom-com or wacky romp?
不如说是青少年恐怖电影
More like teen horror movie.
高中最可怕了
High school is the worst.
课一节比一节难
Classes get super hard,
你的身体也像要跟自己过不去似的
your body just flat-out turns against you,
最糟糕的是  所有人都讨厌你
and worst of all, everybody hates you.
受不了了  新学年撑不过去了
Can't do it. Can't do another year.
老子的荷尔蒙要爆发了
My hormones are like a sweaty cage.
他们不该是唱歌跳舞  赞颂梦想吗
Why aren't they singing about following their dreams?
电视告诉我高中生活是一部音乐剧呢
TV taught me that high school is like some sort of musical.
别让电视给忽悠了
TV lied, man.
如果能逃避长大  赶紧的
If you can avoid growing up, do it.
如果能重回十二岁  让我付出多少都行
I'd give anything to be 12 again.
先不说了  你们来干嘛啊
Anyway, what are you guys doing here?
找一个地方
Just looking for a place
办我的十三岁生日聚会
to have my 13th birthday party.
温蒂・波多莱
Wendy Borduroy?
啊不  科多莱
I mean Corduroy.
科多莱
Corduroy.
明白我的意思了吧
See what I mean?
梅宝宝呼叫迪普普
Master Mabel to Dippity Dog.
我们可以在体育馆开聚会
We can have our party at the gym,
但我想和你谈谈高中的事
but we gotta talk about high school.
我觉得咱们期待的高中生活
I'm starting to think it's might not be
可能没那么美好  完毕
the awesome future we were expecting. Over.
我在死命赶路呢  梅宝
I'm going through a bad patch, Mabel.
等我回来再说吧
We'll talk when I get back... .
迪普  回话  回话
Dipper? Come in, come in?
哎  这样你可能会好受点
Hey, I know what will make you feel better.
一起给朋友们送请贴吧
Let's deliver some invites to your friends, huh?
好啊
Yeah!
梅宝  梅宝  能听见吗
Mabel? Mabel, you there?
听好  迪普  为了一劳永逸封好裂痕
Listen, Dipper, in order to seal the rift for good,
我们需要用到一种粘合剂
it's going to take an adhesive
一种来自地球以外的粘合剂
Something... extraterrestrial in origin.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean?
迪普  看看这些悬崖
Dipper, look at the peculiar shape
不同寻常的形状
made by those cliffs.
是不是想到了什么
Does it remind you of anything?
不会吧
Shut... up
根据我的研究  整个重力泉山谷
According to my research, the entire valley
是由于数百万年前某种地外物体
of Gravity Valley was formed when an extraterrestrial object
的撞击而形成的
crash landed here millions of years ago.
到底是飞碟导致了重力泉的怪诞事件
Did this craft cause the town's strange properties?
还是说  小镇多发的怪诞事件
Or, did the town's strange properties
吸引了飞碟的光临
attract the craft?
答案依然是个谜
The answer is still unknown.
但是这也太疯狂了
But that's crazy!
飞碟到底去哪儿了
Where did the saucer go?
有时候  世界上最诡异之事
Sometimes, the strangest things in the world
就在我们的眼皮底下
are right under our noses.
从我们现在的情况来讲  是脚下
And our feet, in this particular instance.
现在你最好往后站
Now, you might want to stand back.
这把电磁枪的威力
This magnet gun could rip the fillings
能从百米开外虎口掏心
out of a man's mouth from a hundred feet.
我多年来一直从这里搜刮零件
I used to raid this thing for parts for years.
你以为我建传送门的材料是哪来的
Where do you think I got the materials to build my portal?
你  我  说都不会话了
You-- I... words, not working from mouth.
来吧  拿着这个
Now, come. And take this.
别担心  我已经下去过无数次了
Don't worry I've been down here countless times.
那些外星人都死了几百万年了
All the aliens have been dead for millions of years.
大概吧
Probably.
真不敢相信  一直以来
I can't believe there's been a giant UFO
小镇下面都有一个巨型不明飞行物
under the town this whole time.
多希望我的头脑能和你一样年轻啊  迪普
I wish my mind could be where yours is right now, Dipper.
当年证实地外生命存在时  它还算犀利
When confirmation of extraterrestrials still had that punch.
但现在可不比当年了
Now it's just sort of, meh.
我和麦戈科特以前常常下来这里
McGucket and I used to come down here all the time
掠夺他们的科技  学习他们的语言
to raid their tech and study their language.
实在太酷了
This is so cool!
密封裂痕所需的物质
The substance need so seal the rift
是一种外星粘合剂  非常牢固
is an alien adhesive, strong enough to
能把宇宙飞船的船体固定在一起
keep the hull of a spacecraft together.
这种粘合剂只要一滴
Just one dollop of this adhesive
就足够把时空裂痕封住了
should be enough to seal a crack in space-time.
还有就是  如果这东西碰到你
Also, if it touches you, it will seal up
也会把你的脸封成铁板一块
all the orifices in your face,
所以尽量别这么干
so try so avoid that.
好  拿着你的电磁枪跟我来
Now, use your magnet gun and follow me!
-走  -阿福叔公
- Hup. - Great Uncle Ford!
轮到你了
Your turn!
喊声“走”  管用
Say "hup". It helps!
好的  打开磁力  一头跳下去
Okay, just put on magnet, leap down hole.
启动  快点啊
Turn on. Come on already!
磁力启动
Magnet!
帮我一下
A little help?
嗨  梅宝
Oh, hi, Mabel.
你正好赶上我们的一点整男生八卦时间
You're just in time for our one o'clock boy talk.
瞅你们这点追求  看看这个
If you think that's good, boom!
我和迪普的十三岁生日聚会
Me and Dipper's 13th birthday jam!
天啊  你的生日是暑假的最后一天
Oh, man, your birthday's on the last day of summer.
那时我就不在这儿了
I'm not gonna be here.
什么
What?
马吕斯要开飞机带我去奥地利
Marius is flying me out to Austria
让我那周去他的城堡玩什么的
to hang out his castle or whatever that week.
他实在太粘人了
He's co clingy!
我过生日的时候你不在镇上
You're gonna be out of town for my birthday?
但至少你会来的  是吧  糖糖
But at least you can come, right, Candy?
抱歉  梅宝  每年的这个时候
Sorry, Mabel, my parents send me
我父母都要把我送到音乐夏令营去
to music camp this time of year.
音乐夏令营可是逃不掉的
There is no escape from music camp.
这么说你们俩都不能来参加我的生日派对了
So neither of you are gonna be at my birthday party?
而且我们在暑假结束的时候
And you won't be able to wish me good-bye
也没法好好说再见了
at the end of the summer?
真的很抱歉  梅宝
I'm sorry, Mabel.
这个暑假过得太快了
Summer happens so fast.
马吕斯  现在不是时候
Ugh, Marius, now's not the time!
我需要无线电来给我做精神后援
I think I need to radio for emotional backup.
迪普  快回答我
Dipper, please come in.
咱们的派对计划大概要以失败告终了
Our party mission is going down in flames.
完毕
Over.
这里是他们的存储设备
This is their storage facility.
这个地方本该是守卫森严的
This place would have been heavily guarded,
但是现在一切都失效了
but now everything's defunct.
来吧  随便按按钮
Go ahead, flip any switch.
都已经坏了好几百万年了
They've all been busted for millions of years.
克拉拉  你是不是吃了我的农场
Clara, did you eat my farm?
胶水应该就在这附近
The glue should be around here somewhere,
所以睁大你的眼睛
so keep your eyes peeled.
迪普  我想问你点事
Dipper, let me ask you something.
你有没有考虑过你的未来
Have you thought much about your future?
其实没怎么想过
No, not really.
说起来  也就是以优异成绩从高中毕业
I mean, beyond graduating high school with a high GPA
上一所不错的理工院校
so I can get accepted to a good technical college
主修摄影  兼修传媒
with a photography and media production minor
好能做我自己的猎鬼节目
to start my own ghost hunting show.
就像在和年轻的我说话一样
It's like talking to a younger version of myself.
你要是对你的人生目标这么确定
If you're so sure of what you want out of life,
干嘛要浪费时间呢  干嘛要忍受学校的苦差事
why waste? Why put up with the drudgery of school?
呃  相信我  虽然我很想把这一切都加快速度
Huh, trust me, I'd love to fast forward the whole thing, but
但有些事情我没得选
not like I have a choice.
迪普  我一直在想
Dipper, I've been thinking.
我太老了  不能再自己一个人
I'm getting too old to investigate
研究重力泉的秘密
Gravity Falls on my own.
我需要训练一个徒弟来与我共同对抗怪物
I need to train an apprentice to help me fight monsters,
解决神秘事件  保护这个小镇
solve mysteries, and protect this town.
我想在家族内找一个继承人
And I think I'd like to keep it in the family
你说什么
What are you saying?
我读过你对我的日志的注解
I've read your additions to my journal,
我对你的潜力刮目相看
and I'm impressed with your potential.
你觉得暑假过后留在重力泉
What would you say to staying in Gravity Falls
做我的徒弟怎么样
after the summer ends and becoming my apprentice?
那上学的事怎么办
What about school?
迪普  我有十二个博士学位
Dipper, I have 12 PhDs.
由我来给你提供高等教育
Your parents would be thrilled
你父母一定会很高兴的
if I could give you such an advanced education.
还有梅宝
There's also Mabel.
她就会孤身一人在加利福尼亚
She'd be all alone in California.
梅宝自己一个人没问题的
Mabel will be fine on her own.
她有那么招人喜欢的个性
She has a magnetic personality.
我见过她跟一个送披萨的
I watched her become pen pals
迅速投缘成为笔友
with the pizza delivery man
那人才在家门口停了六十秒钟啊
in the 60 seconds he was at the door.
天啊  我们之前还从没分开过呢
Gosh, we've never really been apart before.
这难道不是种束缚吗
And isn't it suffocating?
迪普  你老实告诉我
Dipper, can you honestly tell me
你从没想过有更重大的使命在等着你吗
you never felt like you were meant for something more?
我觉得  我也不清楚
I hav-- I don't know.
听起来就像梦想成真
Sounds like a dream come true,
但是我不知道自己有没有这种天赋
but I'm not sure I have what it takes.
我被比尔骗过
I was tricked by Bill,
我错怪了斯坦的传送门
I was wrong about Stan's portal.
天啊  我甚至连这把电磁枪都用不好
Heck, I can't even operate this magnet gun right.
哈  太好了
Ha! Yes.
迪普  你找到了粘合剂
Dipper, you found the adhesive!
真的吗
I did?
当然是真的了  孩子
Oh-ho, you really did it, kid.
来  咱们拿着这个合张影
Huddle in, let's get a picture of this.
阿福叔公  你不是说这下面的一切都死了吗
Uh, Uncle Ford, you said everything down here is dead, right?
是啊  除非我们不小心激活了
Yes, unless somehow we reactivated the...
安保系统
security system
咱们怎么办
What do we do?
仔细听我说
Listen to me very carefully.
我研究过这个  这些是安保机器人
I've studied these. They're security droids,
会侦测肾上腺素
and they detect adrenaline.
你只要不感到恐惧
You simply have to not feel any fear,
-它们就看不见你  -你说什么
- and they won't see you. - What?
没事的  我以前成功过
It's okay. I've done it before.
深呼一口气  专注  用你的聪明才智
Just take a deep breath, focus on your intellect,
控制你的恐惧
and control your fear.
你说什么  这实在是太疯狂了
Wh-wh-what? that's crazy! I--
照我说的做
Follow my lead!
阿福叔公
Great Uncle ford...
专注  迪普
Focus, Dipper!
我  我
I, uh... I-I-
-我做不到啊  -趴下
- I can't. - Get down!
啊  不
Aah! No! Nooooo...
等等  不要啊
Wait! No!
别过来  太危险了
Stay back. It's too dangerous.
现在封住裂痕才是最重要的
Sealing the rift is what's important now.
拿好这个
Take this.
你要独自一人完成任务了
You're gonna have to do it without me.
使用粘合剂  修复裂痕
Use the adhesive. Fix the rift!
拯救宇宙  迪普
Save the universe, Dipper.
阿福叔公
Great Uncle Ford!
撑住  我来救你了
Hang on, I'm coming for you.
别担心  我会把你救出来的
Don't worry, I'll get you out of there!
那东西要带你去哪儿
Where's that thing taking you?
这是一个全自动监狱机器人
It's an automated prison droid.
不管它去哪儿  我回不来了
And wherever it's going, I'm not coming back.
什么
What?
不行  别走
No, no, no.
别担心  我会想出办法来的
Don't worry, I'll think of something.
迪普  你到底在干什么
Dipper, what on earth are you doing?
坚持住  阿福叔公
Hold on, Great Uncle Ford.
不管怎么样  我都要把你救出来
I'm getting you out of this one way or another.
不要啊
Oh, no!
快点  赶紧
Come on, come on!
放开我的叔公
Let go of my uncle!
噢  不
Oh, no. Aah!
阿福叔公
Great Uncle Ford!
好吧  来试试电磁脉冲
Okay, let's try magna-pulse.
不要  别  不不不不
Oh, no. Oh, no, no, no, no!
拜托  快醒醒
Come on, wake up, man.
我们必须赶紧离开这儿  在
We gotta get out of here before--
喂  我警告你
Hey, I'm warning you!
我可有电磁枪
I have a magnet gun!
是吗  你以为我会怕你
Oh, yeah? You think you can scare me?
放马过来
Do your worst!
在这个宇宙中  没有人能带走我的叔公
Nothing in this universe is gonna take away my uncle.
来啊  让我看看你的本事
So go ahead, Give me what you got.
我以为自己要完蛋了  孩子
I thought I was a goner, kid.
你没事吧  发生什么事了
Are you all right? what happened?
那个球没有检测出任何恐惧的化学迹象
The orb didn't detect any chemical signs of fear.
它以为威胁已经被消除
It assumed the threat was neutralized
就自我解体了
and then self-disassembled.
我  我做到啦
I-- I did it?
你做到了
You did it.
这就是我之前所说的
This is what I was talking about.
你觉得还有多少十二岁的年轻人
How many other 12-year-olds
有能力完成你刚才干的事
do you think are capable of doing what you've just done?
事情还顺利吗  小家伙
Hey, everything all right, pumpkin?
真不敢相信暑假就要结束了
I just can't believe the summer's almost over.
现在我知道了高中生活是多么的糟糕
And now that I know how awful high school's gonna be,
我也不急着要开始经历那场人生悲剧了
I'm in no hurry to start that train wreck.
没人喜欢变老
Nobody likes getting older.
不过年龄的增长
But just because you're growing up
并不意味着你必须长大  懂吗
doesn't mean you have to grow up, you know?
我是说  看看我  都快七十了
I mean, look at me. I'm pushing 70,
晚餐依然吃冰淇淋
and I still eat ice cream for dinner.
但是我不想和重力泉告别
But I don't want to say good-bye to Gravity Falls.
嘿  至少这个暑假之后  不管发生什么事
Hey, at least whatever happens after this summer,
你的弟弟依然会陪着你
you'll still have your brother along with you
赴汤蹈火  在所不辞
through thick and thin.
不是每个人都能有那种体验  你知道么
Not everyone can say that, you know.
对  至少当我回家时
Yeah. At least when I go home
我总是有迪普相伴
I always have Dipper.
这个小可爱  我的小依靠
Good old reliable old...
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我扶你从这儿出来
Let's get you out of there.
听我说  迪普  这个小镇有种磁力
Listen to me, Dipper, this town is a magnet
它吸引着特别的东西
for things that are special.
也包括你和我
And that includes you and me.
它送我们两个来这里  是天命的安排
It brought both of us here for a purpose.
和我一起留下来吧  迪普
Stay here with me, Dipper.
成为我的徒弟
Become my apprentice.
别让任何人阻拦你
Don't let anyone hold you--
我答应你  我会留下来的
I'll do it. I'm gonna stay.
好极了
Excellent.
现在  谁想去拯救世界  乖徒弟
Now, who wants to save the world, apprentice?
梅宝  我刚刚经历了生命中最棒的一天
Mabel, I just had the best day of my life.
飞碟是真实存在的  镇子下面就有一个
UFOs are real, and there's one under the town,
我还救了阿福叔公  而且
and I saved Great Uncle Ford's life and--
嘿  你还好吗
Hey, are you okay?
告诉我这不是真的  迪普
Tell me it's not true, Dipper.
告诉我你是在开玩笑
Tell me you were joking.
阿福的徒弟  你是认真的吗
Ford's apprentice? Seriously?
听着  我只是在考虑  而且这事
Look, I was thinking, and this is
对我来说是个大好机会
a huge opportunity for me.
对我来说却是个大坏的机会
Well, it's a horrible opportunity for me!
我经历了我人生中最糟糕的一天
I had the worst day of my life.
当十三岁到来的时候  暑假结束了
When we turn 13, the summer ends,
我不得不抛下这一切
and I have to leave everything behind.
你就是我唯一的依靠
You're the only person I could count on,
而现在你也要离开我了吗
and now you're leaving me, too?
听我说  这事我考虑过
Look, I've been thinking about it.
我又不是要永远离开  好吗
I won't be gone forever, okay?
我还是会回家看你
I'll still visit you at home
我们能在网上聊天  这事是可以解决的
and we'll chat online-- we'll make it work.
我不想解决这事
I don't want it to work.
我就想让这个暑假永远持续下去
I just wish summer could last forever.
但这不可能  梅宝
But it can't, Mabel.
听着  世界不可能永远定格在这一刻
Look, things aren't gonna stay frozen this way.
这是成长的一部分
It's part of growing up.
势不可挡
Things change.
寒来暑往
Summer ends.
梅宝  等等
Mabel, wait!
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean it like that.
梅宝  快回来
Mabel, come back!
现在只有聚会巧克力能让我高兴点儿了
Only party chocolate can cheer me up now.
宅男图书  被啃过的笔
Nerd books? Chewed up pens?
噢  拿错了包
Ugh, wrong backpack.
这不公平
It's not fair.
我只希望暑假永不结束
I just wish summer could last forever.
说不定有可能
That might be possible.
毛衣城现在拒接电话
Sweater Town is not accepting incoming calls right now.
梅  梅  梅宝  是我
M-M-Mabel, it's me.
什么  谁在说话
What? Who said that?
我能帮助你
I can help.
那个时间旅行的家伙
The time travel guy?
你在这里干嘛呢
What are you doing here?
你说你不想让暑假结束  对吗
You said you don't want summer to end, right?
我没听错吧
Did I hear that right?
没错
Yeah.
为什么要这么问
Why are you asking?
听着  虽然这可能违反规定
Look, maybe it's against the rules,
但是你曾经帮助过我
but you once did a favor for me, so
所以我觉得应该回报你
I thought I could help you out.
有一种时间泡泡
It's called a time bubble,
它能阻止时光流逝
and it prevents time from going forward.
在重力泉的暑假  你想要多久就有多久
Summer in Gravity Falls can last as long as you want it to.
真的吗  这东西怎么用
Really? But how does it work.
我只需要你到你叔公那里给我拿个小玩意儿
I just need you to get a little gizmo for me from your uncle.
是个小东西  他都不会发现它不见了
Something small-- he won't even know it's missing.
也许迪普的呆子袋里会有那种东西
Huh, maybe Dipper has something like that in his nerd bag.
让我猜猜  梅宝无法坦然接受吧
Let me guess. Mabel didn't take it well?
我  我不知道
I--I don't know.
也许我在做错误的决定
Maybe I'm making the wrong decision.
我得好好考虑这件事
I need to think about this.
迪普  我们现在应该集中精力在任务上
Dipper, right now we need to focus on the mission.
来吧  我把粘合剂拿来了
Now, come on. I've got the glue.
把裂痕给我  让我们史册留名
Hand me the rift and let's make history.
什么
What?
不  裂痕
Oh, no, the rift!
好奇怪啊
Huh. That's odd.
是这个吗  对  就是这个
Is this it? Yes, that's it!
快给我  我好来帮你
Just hand it over and I'll do my thing.
除非你准备离开重力泉
Unless you're ready to leave Gravity Falls.
只要夏天长一点点就行
Just a little more summer.
什么
What?
不  等等  等等  等一下
Oh, no! Wait, wait, wait!
不容易啊  总算成了
At last. At long, long last!
两个世界之间的门开啦
The gate between worlds is open!
十亿年前预言的大事件要来啦
The event one billion years prophesized has come to pass!
等到这一天啦  这个世界终于是我的啦
The day has come. The world is finally mine!
发生了什么事
What's going on?
那是什么
What is that?
我们迟了
We're too late.
世界末日到了
It's the end of the world.